<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>certification on Hi, I&#39;m Rob.</title>
    <link>https://robscharf.github.io/tags/certification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in certification on Hi, I&#39;m Rob.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 12:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robscharf.github.io/tags/certification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I passed the OSCP!</title>
      <link>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/may-10-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/may-10-2023/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to share that I recently passed the the Penetration Testing with Kali Linux certification exam on May 10 (on my first attempt)!
The Exam According to OffSec&amp;rsquo;s website:
The industry-leading Penetration Testing with Kali Linux (PWK/PEN-200) course introduces penetration testing methodologies, tools and techniques via hands-on experience and is self-paced. Learners who complete the course and pass the exam will earn the OffSec Certified Professional (OSCP) certification which requires holders to successfully attack and penetrate various live machines in a safe lab environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I passed the PNPT!</title>
      <link>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/november-28-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/november-28-2022/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to share that I recently passed the Practical Network Penetration Tester certification exam on November 6!
The Exam According to TCM&amp;rsquo;s website:
The PNPT certification exam is a one-of-a-kind ethical hacking certification exam that assesses a student’s ability to perform an external and internal network penetration test at a professional level. Students will have five (5) full days to complete the assessment and an additional two (2) days to write a professional report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I passed the eJPT!</title>
      <link>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/june-20-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robscharf.github.io/blog/june-20-2022/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to share that I recently passed the eLearnSecurity Junior Penetration Tester certification exam on June 16!
The Exam According to INE&amp;rsquo;s website:
The eJPT is a three day, 20 question exam, that focuses on challenging you to prove your skillset in penetration testing foundations including programming, networking vulnerabilities, web attack vectors, and a host of other entry level skills&amp;hellip; Covering a host of skills which include entry level web penetration techniques, the eJPT provides you with the confidence and knowledge to begin training for more advanced penetration techniques and specialities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
